You sure are
a member of what Bert the turtle just
good friends because every one of us must
remember to do the same thing
that's what this film is all about
and cover this is an official civil defense
film produced in cooperation with the
Federal Civil Defense administration
and in consultation with the Safety
Commission of the National Education
Association produced by Archer
Productions Incorporated
meet all these nice people play a
ride. I really can't blame you.
You see Byrd is a very very
careful fella and has danger.
This is the way he keeps from being
hurt sometimes it even saves his life.
That's why these children
are practicing to duck
and cover just as you do in your school.
We all know the atomic
bomb is very dangerous.
Since it may be used against us we must
get ready for it just as we are ready for
many other dangers that are around
us all the time fire is a danger.
It can burn whole buildings. If someone
is careless. But we are ready for fire.
We have a fine fire department
to put out the fire.
And you have fire drills in your
school. So you know what to do.
I don't feel it can be dangerous to
sometimes cause bad accidents. We already.
We have safety rules that car drivers
and people who are walking must obey.
Now we must be ready for a
new danger. The atomic bomb.
First you have to know what happens
when an atomic bomb explodes.
You will know when it comes. We hope
it never comes. But when I get ready.
It looks something like this there is a
bright flash brighter than the sun brighter
than anything you've ever seen. If you are
not ready and did not know what to do.
It could hurt you in different
ways it could knock it down hard
or throw you against a tree or a
wall. It is such a big explosion.
It can smash in buildings
and knock signboards over
and break windows all
over town but if you duck
and cover like bird you will be much safer
if you know how bad sunburn can feel the
atomic bomb flash could burn you
worse than a terrible sunburn.
Especially when you are not covered.
Now you
and I don't have shells to crawl into like
birds the turtles all we have to cover
up in our own way first
duck and then cover
and very tightly you cover
the back of your neck.
If your face duck and cover
underneath the table or desk
or anything else close by and
that the school they are talking about the
atomic bomb to Betty is asking a teacher.
How can we tell when the atomic bomb they
explode and our teacher is explaining
that there are two kinds of attack with
a warning and without any warning.
I think that most of the time we will
be warned before the bomb explodes.
So there will be time for us
to get into our homes schools
or some other safe place our civil defense
workers know a man in uniform will do
everything they can to warn us before
enemy planes can bring a bomb near you.
Maybe in your school yard
playing when the signal calm.
Signal means to stop
whatever you are doing
and get to the nearest safe place fact
always remember an atomic bomb can
come at any time no matter where you
are maybe you might be playing at home
when the warning comes your
to get in the house fast
to fix a safe place for you to
go if you're not close to home
when you hear the warning go to the nearest
safe cover know where you are to go
or ask an older person to help you
know the places marked with A.S.I.
and There are safe places to go
when you hear the alarm if there is a
warning you will hear it before the bomb
explodes. But sometimes and
this is very very important.
Sometimes the bomb might
explode without any warning.
Then the first thing we would know
about it would be the flash and
that means duck and cover
fast wherever you are.
There's no time to look around or wait
like Bert when there is a flash duck
and cover and do it fast.
Here are some older boys showing
what to do with the flash comes
when you are not in the classroom.
This is what to do if you
should be in a corridor.
Duck and cover tight
against the wall this way.
Remember to keep your face in the back
of your neck covered tightly try to find
away from windows or doors with glass
in them and if the glass breaks
and flies through the
air. It won't cut you.
You might be eating your lunch
when the place comes duck
and cover under the table then if the
explosion makes anything in the room fall
down. It can fall on you.
Getting ready means we will all have to
be able to take care of ourselves a bomb
might explode when there are no
grownups near Poland that you know this
and they are always ready to take
care of themselves. Here they are.
On their way to school on a beautiful
spring day but no matter where they go
or what they do they always try to remember
what to do if the atom bomb explodes
right then it's a bomb can cover.
Paul and Patty know what to do.
Paul covered the back of his head
so that he wouldn't be burned
and Patty covered herself with the coat
she was carrying they knew how to duck
and cover they acted right
away when the flash came.
If they had been at this doorway
when the bomb flashed Paul
and Pat A would have ducked
and covered this way like this girl
heavy doorways are a good place to duck
and cover. She will be safer too. Here's
Tony going to his Cub Scout meeting.
Tony knows the bomb can explode
any time of the year day
or night he is ready for it
can cover at a bride only
that flash means act fast. Tony knows that
it helps to get to any kind of cover.
This wall was close by. So that's
where he ducked and covered.
Tony knew what to do.
Notice how he keeps from moving
or from getting up and running.
He stays down until you're sure the danger
is over the man helping Tony is a civil
defense worker his job is to help protect
us from there is danger of the atomic
bomb. We must obey the
civil defense worker.
We must know how to duck and cover in
the school bus or in any other bus
or streetcar. Don't wait duck
away from the windows fast.
The glass may break and
flying through the air
and cut you Sundays holidays they
Cajun time. We must be ready.
Every day all the time
to do the right thing.
If the atomic bomb explodes.
This family knows what to do just
like your own family should they know
that even a thin cloth helps protect them
even a newspaper can save you from a.
Bad burn but the most important
thing of all is to duck
and cover yourself especially
when your clothes do not cover you no
matter where we live in the city of the
country. We must be ready. All the time
for the atomic bomb that can cover.
That's the first thing to do duck
and cover the next important
thing to do after
that is to stay covered
until the danger is over.
Yes we must all get ready now.
So we know how to save ourselves at the
atomic bomb ever explodes near us.
If you do not know just
what to do ask your teacher
when this film is over discuss what
you could do in different places.
If a bomb explodes older people
will help us as they always do but
that might not be any grownups
around when the bomb explodes.
Then you're on your own.
Remember what you do not
tell me right out loud
when you talk.